<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on norbu09</title>
    <link>http://lnz.me/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on norbu09</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lnz.me/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>a new view</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/03/09/a-new-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/03/09/a-new-view/</guid>
      <description>We are starting a new experiment in our life, it is called &amp;ldquo;project mountain retreat&amp;rdquo;. The back story to this experiment is that Manu, ever since we first were in St Arnaud and looked at Lake Rotoiti, loved this place and it felt very much at home for me right away. It took us years to come back to this place but now we plan to stay a bit longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burnout and how to see it</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/02/02/burnout-and-how-to-see-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/02/02/burnout-and-how-to-see-it/</guid>
      <description>I read Derek Sivers post Getting out of a bad place today and it made me clean up my blog, re-launch it, collect a few old posts I had scattered around and release a post that I, myself, had only shared privately so far. It is about my history with work-till-you-drop and my history with a mind that is driven to continue well past the point where it is productive or healthy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>real geeks die early</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2010/05/05/every-once-in-a-while/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2010/05/05/every-once-in-a-while/</guid>
      <description>real geeks die early every once in a while i stumble upon an article from someone pointing out the dangers we geeks live in in terms of unhealthy work hours and our very own unhealthy mind set.
I am a developer for profit since the late 90s and a team lead since the early 2000s. i&amp;rsquo;ve seen a fair amount of problems and have done my fair share of work during nights, weekends and my holidays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>many of us know it ...</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2009/02/09/many-of-us-know-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2009/02/09/many-of-us-know-it/</guid>
      <description>i guess many of us geeks went through the one or other phase in their life when they felt themselves trapped in the system with no way out. &amp;ldquo;the system&amp;rdquo; meaning any kind of mental state that prevented a clear view on the situation.
brenda just posted this URL and i can only encourage all to read it. keep it in mind and have a look at it when feeling unsure if that all out there that seems to lock you in is &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; or just you looking the wrong way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>