<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on norbu09</title>
    <link>http://lnz.me/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on norbu09</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lnz.me/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>a new view</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/03/09/a-new-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/03/09/a-new-view/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are starting a new experiment in our life, it is called &amp;ldquo;project
mountain retreat&amp;rdquo;. The back story to this experiment is that Manu,
ever since we first were in St Arnaud and looked at Lake Rotoiti, loved
this place and it felt very much at home for me right away. It took us
years to come back to this place but now we plan to stay a bit longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the Europe experiment showed we really don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy the city life for
much more than a couple of days, after that we really like the calm and
quiet of more remote places. When we took out the lease at our current
place we knew it would only be for a few months and planned to build a
tiny house and put it on the south island and go between there and
Wellington to have the best of both worlds. Looking for places we found
a cute little mountain retreat that offered all we wanted but was
already built. Not a tiny house, and that plan is really only postponed
a bit, but a little hut in the mountains, just outside of St Arnaud. It
is calm and far away and still close enough to Wellington that we can
enjoy the city life for a couple of days a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will report here on progress and learnings from this experiment. It feels
like going on an adventure and a bit like getting back some of the things
I started missing, like actual winters and ski fields around the corner,
but still have the sandy beaches of the Able Tasman region on our door step.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burnout and how to see it</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/02/02/burnout-and-how-to-see-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/02/02/burnout-and-how-to-see-it/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I read Derek Sivers post &lt;a href=&#34;http://sivers.org/bad&#34;&gt;Getting out of a bad
place&lt;/a&gt; today and it made me clean up my blog,
re-launch it, collect a few old posts I had scattered around and release
a post that I, myself, had only shared privately so far. It is about my
history with work-till-you-drop and my history with a mind that is
driven to continue well past the point where it is productive or
healthy. I hope it is a post that makes you think if you are in a
similar situation or, even more important, helps you realise you are in
a bad place. A friend I shared this post with recently wrote to me a few
months after meeting him and told me that this made him realise that he
was way down that track already without seeing it. He made drastic
changes to his life and is a way happier person now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-burnout&#34;&gt;About burnout&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my live I have worked quite a lot so far. Many would say I have also
achieved a lot but funny enough for me that never felt that way. I had
my first burnout age 30. I hit rock bottom, knew I had to change
something and decided to kill my career and start from scratch. I
thought that at that time I had learned enough to start again, do
something else and just spend my time enjoying live again. Many who
knew me at that time did not notice that I was a wrack, that I had
massive issues with depression and was just focusing on external
problems to not having to deal with myself. It was a pretty dark time
for me even though my career was going well and the company I worked for
was pretty successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved on, recovered, bootstrapped my live in a new country, working
for someone else and just enjoyed life. Thing is, it was actually quite
boring so I started working on a little side project. That side project
turned into a company, that company needed money so I started another
company to finance the first and a few years down the road I noticed
that I had fallen into the same trap I was in before. This time I knew a
bit more and maybe saw my situation in a different light. I knew that I
had to change something but I also knew that I had amazing teams to
rely on and the support from my partner who is never tired to look after
me. She already supported me through my first melt down and not
only helped me build our companies but also always looked after me never
mind which state I was in. I know today that thanks to the people around
me I can get back on my feet, do less, focus on myself more and still
contribute to my companies in a meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick side story, I was in Scotland recently and we did a bit of
hiking. I have not done any hiking in anger in a long time and we
decided to hike up Ben Nevis, the highest mountain in the UK. It is a 4h
hike up and a 3h hike down over a pretty shitty path with large boulders
and it really is not that dramatic but in my physical condition it was
way too much for me. Now, my body told me about half way up that this is
not going to work but my mind totally did not accept that. I was up
there, it was amazing, after I got up from that big bolder I was lying
on and slept for an hour, then tried to eat some which I nearly vomited
right away - I did not listen to my body. My fear of being inferior and
me being determined to get up there did serious harm to my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back at my downward spiral experiences I see many analogies, I
did not listen to my body and that took its toll. This time round I got
away without depressions, maybe because I know in the meantime how to
deal with them, maybe because I already suffered from massive anxiety
and claustrophobia. It was not a pretty time and I hope that anyone who
goes through a time like this has a strong partner at his side that
gives them the support to pull themselves out of that again. I have that
strong partner at my side and am very lucky that I managed, thanks to
her, to pull myself out again and listen to my body more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that I&amp;rsquo;ll find my balance at some stage, I certainly know the
signs and know how it feels when I am there but hopefully I will not
forget to listen to my body. I can really only highly urge everyone who
works in a fast paced company to sit back every now and then, reflect
and check if what you do is healthy. Pace is not everything, you only
got this one live and the mad rush of fast growing companies is amazing
but you need to know when to change your mode of running it and when to
change your pace. Running a company is a long term thing and it is only
rewarding if you are on that peak and enjoy the view without that
desire to vomit and sleep or to just hope that a helicopter comes around
the corner to pick you up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>real geeks die early</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2010/05/05/every-once-in-a-while/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2010/05/05/every-once-in-a-while/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;real-geeks-die-early&#34;&gt;real geeks die early&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;every once in a while i &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.skorks.com/2010/02/did-your-boss-thank-you-for-coding-yourself-to-death/&#34;&gt;stumble upon an article&lt;/a&gt; from someone pointing
out the dangers we geeks live in in terms of unhealthy work hours
and our very own unhealthy mind set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a developer for profit since the late 90s and a team lead since the
early 2000s. i&amp;rsquo;ve seen a fair amount of problems and have done my
fair share of work during nights, weekends and my holidays. it was
expected as part of my work and i was immature enough to not turn it
down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when i look down the road i came from i&amp;rsquo;ve lost a very good friend due
to depressions which were mainly coming from a very unhealthy work
environment and some more not so close friends either to heart attacks
or they suffered serious burn out syndromes that changed their ability
to work entirely. only weeks ago a friend of mine died after a heart
attack and he was only my age. our industry is seriously in trouble, we
set the wrong incentives and we abuse our developers as if we were in
the industrial revolution in the late 1900s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the problem is that managers will never understand that programming is
not like building a car, you take some parts and can roughly estimate
when it is assembled. geeks invent cars (to stick with the
analogy) and inventing things is not as predictable as simply assembling
stuff. as much as we think we can judge things we are either way above
or way beyond the real time spent. as we normally love what we are doing
we take this risk and try to finish in time even if we are way off with
what we estimated. the problem with inventing is that it can always go
either way, we find that very simple solution simply like that or we
can&amp;rsquo;t see it till months after the deadline. a manager has to deliver in
time - which is bollocks, it is never so time critical anyway - but a
developer has to invent that thing and deliver in time. once you are
behind schedule there is the pressure and the coding and normally this
is when quality suffers the most and the most unhealthy time is spent.
the manager keeps pushing you but he will not stay up till 2am sitting
next to you and help you code that beast. he is the one that sits
between you and the customer and has to fight off trouble - but he is
doing that between 9am and 5pm. i am not saying that either one of the
two is doing a more valuable job (i was on either side), i only want to
stress that healthy working times are essential and neglecting social
interaction which comes from long working hours will kill you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it either kills you very directly with heart attacks or slightly less
deadly but still killing your career with burn outs and nervous
breakdowns or it kills you more indirect with depressions that can lead
to suicide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i changed my personal rat race some years ago with killing my career and
deciding that life is more about living than piling up status symbols.
funny enough since then so many new opportunities arose that i am way
better off today than i was then. working only healthy hours is
essential for your life and social interaction is key to survive as a
developer!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>many of us know it ...</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2009/02/09/many-of-us-know-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2009/02/09/many-of-us-know-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;i guess many of us geeks went through the one or other phase in their
life when they felt themselves trapped in the system with no way out.
&amp;ldquo;the system&amp;rdquo; meaning any kind of mental state that prevented a clear
view on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;brenda just posted this URL and i can only encourage all to read it.
keep it in mind and have a look at it when feeling unsure if that all
out there that seems to lock you in is &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; or just you looking the
wrong way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;trust me, most of the time it is you, the rest of the time it helps to
step back and look at the bigger picture. lets face it, we are a strange
breed but we can do things the programmatic way, just think of it from
time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bluehackers.org &amp;hellip; brilliant job&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>