<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Startup on norbu09</title>
    <link>http://lnz.me/tags/startup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Startup on norbu09</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 10:06:48 +1200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lnz.me/tags/startup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Community and walled gardens</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/post/2017-05-02-community-and-walled-gardens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 10:06:48 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/post/2017-05-02-community-and-walled-gardens/</guid>
      <description>I have helped build and contribute to the NZ startup community since around 2008 and during that time have been granted access to many groups, back channels, side channels, communication channels that I signed up to or got signed up to and it continues, every new group that forms starts creating yet another mailing list and slack channel and Facebook group.
Over the years we have created this monster that looks very open and approachable from the inside but gives no clues on how to join it from the outside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How could a post Silicon Valley startup scene look like</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2017/01/13/post-silicon-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 23:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2017/01/13/post-silicon-valley/</guid>
      <description>I did a lot of thinking about ways how we could build a more humane and inclusive startup scene in New Zealand but the recent events in the US made me think a little bigger. These ideas are very much a &amp;ldquo;thinking in progress&amp;rdquo; so please give me feedback on them so we can push this idea forward. This is where I am at:
Looking at what we currently call digital nomads and the emergence of remote first companies, how relevant are location, political systems and financial hubs in a post Silicon Valley startup scene?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About perception</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2017/01/17/about-perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2017/01/17/about-perception/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a post about perception and my &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t complain but fix&amp;rdquo; policy for this year over at the iwantmyname blog. Head over to the iwantmyname blog and tweet your comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>founder.chat - growing a community</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2016/01/11/founder-dot-chat-growing-a-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2016/01/11/founder-dot-chat-growing-a-community/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Thursday, 14th January 2016, 5:30 at Bridge Street
I am passionate about community and passionate about empowering people to realise their ideas, as opposed to just talking about them. I am also keen to bring together people so that they can help each other.
New year, new challenge. My personal challenge for this year is to build a robust and well connected entrepreneurial fabric in Nelson and create a blueprint for regions outside the major centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Entrepreneurship Week</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/11/18/global-entrepreneurship-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/11/18/global-entrepreneurship-week/</guid>
      <description>I care about entrepreneurship because I believe in the power of collaboration and the power of people working together for fun and profit, quite literally. I see entrepreneurship as a way to create resilient communities that address problems by working together, by building companies, by creating work for others and by investing back into the community. Entrepreneurs are people that have a vision and are crazy enough to follow that vision, passionate enough to infect others with their idea and make them form a team around a common interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview for #TGASW15</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/10/22/interview-for-number-tgasw15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/10/22/interview-for-number-tgasw15/</guid>
      <description>I gave an interview about Startup Weekends and what draws me to them. Read it on the Venture Centre blog and tweet your comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>upcoming Startup Weekends</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/06/05/upcoming-startup-weekends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/06/05/upcoming-startup-weekends/</guid>
      <description>There are two Startup Weekends coming up in Hawkes Bay and Taurange. Startup Weekends are a perfect opportunity to learn how to transform an idea to a MVP, a minimal viable product. Startup Weekends are a crash course in entrepreneurschip over a weekend in a sheltered environment and with near to no financial implications. The costs, in fact, are often not even covering the food and drinks provided during the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/21/communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/21/communication/</guid>
      <description>When starting a company there is a lot of stuff that needs to be looked at. There are lots of things that need your attention and many things will not be talked about because there is simply no time for it. This can very easily lead to a habit of not communicating with everyone in the team. Another frequent problem is that from your own point of view a lot of things are very obvious and you just can&amp;rsquo;t understand how someone in your team can&amp;rsquo;t see it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get advice</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/20/how-to-get-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/20/how-to-get-advice/</guid>
      <description>A key task for any co-founder is getting advice. Especially if you are new to something it is key to ask. It is important to understand that others have more experience in things that you will bang your head against. Getting advice is key to a successful start and helps you keep on track, helps you grow and helps you reposition yourself. Advice is a key ingredient for many of the most successful entrepreneurs and not getting advice is a silly thing to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>leading by example</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/14/leading-by-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/14/leading-by-example/</guid>
      <description>Leadership is a tricky thing and over the years I have tried different styles and was exposed to different styles. I have observed many every successful people and people in high positions that lead big companies.
I found that most leaders fall into two categories. Leader by example and leader by position. What I mean with that is people that live and breath what they demand from their team, people that are respected for what they know and people that don&amp;rsquo;t have to hide behind a title to be accepted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic vs extrinsic motivation</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/13/intrinsic-vs-extrinsic-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/13/intrinsic-vs-extrinsic-motivation/</guid>
      <description>I have mentored at Startup Weekend Auckland last weekend and noticed an interesting pattern. Participants that were at the weekend with the goal to win the competition were less motivated in the teams they were in if they thought the team is not doing well. Participants that were at the weekend primarily to learn something and did not care too much about winning were highly motivated and performed really well. Teams consisting exclusively out of participants who wanted to learn were very receptive to external input and managed to deliver a very good product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to end a conversation with me</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/08/how-to-end-a-conversation-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/08/how-to-end-a-conversation-with-me/</guid>
      <description>I get quite a few people that ask me for advice on technical co-founders or how to find a technical person for their startup. The one sentence that ends a conversation with me needing to urgently attend another meeting or some other way of getting away in a polite way is the following:
&amp;ldquo;I know how to do idea X; I only need a technical person to build it for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting into habits</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/07/getting-into-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/07/getting-into-habits/</guid>
      <description>Habits structure your life. Knowing your habits and training new habits can be real challenging and a lot of books have been written about how to get into habits that help you achieve your goals. Thing is, like most new year resolutions, it is real hard to stick to a habit and make it stick around.
I have recently started playing HabitRPG and challenged my partner to join me. We now battle us for points to things like drinking enough water during the day or go running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to start?</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/04/25/where-to-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/04/25/where-to-start/</guid>
      <description>I often get asked what non-technical co-founders should start with till they have found a technical co-founder. Mostly followed by, &amp;ldquo;where can I find a technical co-founder&amp;rdquo;.
This is an interesting topic as quite often I see the non-technical co-founders seeing their role in telling a tech guy what to do who then magically turns it into working code. Unfortunately this is not quite how it works and as a non-technical co-founder joining a startup without any understanding what it means to write software and to build a startup will most probably end in tears.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>