<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Startup on norbu09</title>
    <link>http://lnz.me/tags/startup/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Startup on norbu09</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <atom:link href="http://lnz.me/tags/startup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How could a post Silicon Valley startup scene look like</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2017/01/13/post-silicon-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 23:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2017/01/13/post-silicon-valley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did a lot of thinking about ways how we could build a more humane and
inclusive startup scene in New Zealand but the recent events in the US
made me think a little bigger. These ideas are very much a &amp;ldquo;thinking in
progress&amp;rdquo; so please give me feedback on them so we can push this idea
forward. This is where I am at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at what we currently call digital nomads and the emergence of
remote first companies, how relevant are location, political systems and
financial hubs in a post Silicon Valley startup scene?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to postulate a very provocative &amp;ldquo;not at all&amp;rdquo;. Looking at
iwantmyname, we have people in New Zealand, USA, Canada, Sweden, Austria
and Germany at the moment, Over the years we have been approached by
investors from many countries, some from the obvious financial centers but
also from places that I would call &amp;ldquo;emerging markets&amp;rdquo;. We hire by talent
not by location and I travel a lot and work from various places, so do
many in our company. Location became one of the many parameters
describing my current situation but it is not a defining one and
certainly not constant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the current startup scene through the lens of a startup
mentor I would suggest to someone creating a new scene to disrupt the
established system with fresh ideas that fit this new reality. If we
take Silicon Valley as the old incumbent and push for a new niche, a
truly distributed but well connected startup scene that is based on a
solid foundation of core values rather than an investment model seems
like a good niche to start with. I would be keen to try something like
that and would back a new, post Silicon Valley startup scene like that
with my time and experience and networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An antifragile startup scene that can&amp;rsquo;t be disrupted by changing
political systems because we can simply switch to new countries, work
out of new co-working spaces, join new physical communities, learn
from them, then take that learning with us to the next and the next
place. A scene that does not need temples for the egos of the founders in
the form of massive office buildings but rather lets people work from
where they want because the output matters, not their attendance. If we
take all this and pour it into a founding fabric of values, would that
be a scene you want to be associated with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ping me on twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/norbu09&#34;&gt;@norbu09&lt;/a&gt; if you want
to discuss this in more detail or have ideas how we can push these ideas
further into the mainstream. Please point me to people thinking along
the same lines, show me the existing networks already doing this without
me knowing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>founder.chat - growing a community</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2016/01/11/founder-dot-chat-growing-a-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2016/01/11/founder-dot-chat-growing-a-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TL;DR: Thursday, 14th January 2016, 5:30 at Bridge Street&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am passionate about community and passionate about empowering people
to realise their ideas, as opposed to just talking about them. I am also
keen to bring together people so that they can help each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New year, new challenge. My personal challenge for this year is to build
a robust and well connected entrepreneurial fabric in Nelson and create
a blueprint for regions outside the major centers. There is loads of
entrepreneurial spirit in the regions but it is not well connected yet
and typically gets together once a year for events like Startup Weekend
but not much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://founder.chat&#34;&gt;founder.chat&lt;/a&gt; is a weekly meetup that happens at
Bridge Street on Thursdays at 5:30. It is open to everyone, no signup
required, just come around, no fee, no koha, no barriers to entry other
than you making time to show up. We&amp;rsquo;ll do a quick round of intros every
time and then work together on a few problems within the group. This
could be setting up a social media campaign, set up a landing page, look
into A/B testing or get help with book keeping or a legal problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time I hope we can grow that fabric that whenever someone needs
help they know who to talk to, in person, face-to-face. Community is
what remains after the politicians, the investors and the people with an
agenda left. My goal is to grow a fabric that is robust and long lived
so that we can make sure it lives on for a long time. An open community
is also something no one owns. It needs a few people to kick it off but
once it lives there is no stopping it. Help me to get it started and
help me to transform the Nelson region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are starting the new year with the first meetup this Thursday, 14th
of January 2016 at 5:30 at Bridge Street. Come around, tell us what you
are working on or what you plan to work on and what you need help with.
After a bit of helping each other we&amp;rsquo;ll go to a nearby Pub and have a
social wind down with a cool beverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions, hit me up on Twitter (@norbu09)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Entrepreneurship Week</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/11/18/global-entrepreneurship-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/11/18/global-entrepreneurship-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I care about entrepreneurship because I believe in the power of
collaboration and the power of people working together for fun and
profit, quite literally. I see entrepreneurship as a way to create
resilient communities that address problems by working together, by
building companies, by creating work for others and by investing back
into the community. Entrepreneurs are people that have a vision and are
crazy enough to follow that vision, passionate enough to infect others
with their idea and make them form a team around a common interest.
Entrepreneurs are people who create and are never satisfied with the
status quo. People that start sentences with &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rdquo; not with &amp;ldquo;Someone
should&amp;rdquo; and this makes them the engines of innovation. They turn ideas
into teams into companies. Innovation only happens if someone steps up
and runs with a new idea and has enough passion to turn that idea
into a viable business. Profit can have any form or colour, some are
after the money but most entrepreneurs I have met are after the rewards
that come with building companies. The reward of creating jobs for
people, the reward of creating opportunities for people, the reward of
seeing a crazy idea grow into a viable business. All this is why I spend
many weekends every year at Startup Weekends, this is why I have coffees
with people who want advice. Growing the entrepreneurial fabric is
something I am very passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that a high level of entrepreneurship creates resilient
communities way beyond influential people, companies or politicians. I
care about the world I live in and want to play my part in creating a
future worth living for. Join me in encouraging more people to give it a
go, to try to take their future and the future of their community into
their own hands. Join me in building resilient communities. There are
plenty of activities happening, ping me if you struggle to find them and
I&amp;rsquo;ll hook you up with your local community leaders or help you become
that person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview for #TGASW15</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/10/22/interview-for-number-tgasw15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/10/22/interview-for-number-tgasw15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I gave an interview about Startup Weekends and what draws me to them.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://venturecentre.co.nz/blog/startup-weekend/item/108-i-ve-just-had-a-life-changing-experience-tgasw15&#34;&gt;Read it on the Venture Centre blog&lt;/a&gt; and tweet your comments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>upcoming Startup Weekends</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/06/05/upcoming-startup-weekends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/06/05/upcoming-startup-weekends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are two Startup Weekends coming up in Hawkes Bay and Taurange.
Startup Weekends are a perfect opportunity to learn how to transform an
idea to a MVP, a minimal viable product. Startup Weekends are a crash
course in entrepreneurschip over a weekend in a sheltered environment
and with near to no financial implications. The costs, in fact, are
often not even covering the food and drinks provided during the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upcoming startup weekends in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://hawkesbay.startupweekend.org/&#34;&gt;Hawkes Bay&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://tauranga.startupweekend.org/&#34;&gt;Tauranga&lt;/a&gt; are on
the weekend of the 28th of June and following weekend of the 5th of July
respectively. Make sure you show up at one of them if you are in the
region and plan to push your idea to the next stage. We have world class
mentors at both events and we will definitely have a lot of fun and
learn a lot over these two weekends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/21/communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/21/communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When starting a company there is a lot of stuff that needs to be looked
at. There are lots of things that need your attention and many things
will not be talked about because there is simply no time for it. This can
very easily lead to a habit of not communicating with everyone in the
team. Another frequent problem is that from your own point of view a lot
of things are very obvious and you just can&amp;rsquo;t understand how someone in
your team can&amp;rsquo;t see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If left untreated this will become a big ugly scar and can break
successful teams over time. Communication is a tricky thing, it needs a
lot of attention to detail and needs a lot of time to get right. Every
new addition to your team will change communication and will need new
ways of communication. The one thing that is the most tricky is
understanding and always coming back to the fact that we are all human,
we make errors and it is often hard to talk with someone who you think
is in the wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always try to address communication issues by asking myself what can I
do to fix this, what can I do to address a lack of communication. I
always try to be the one initiating the conversation again after
something went wrong or something did not work out the way we planned.
Communication is key, keep it up, talk to each other, always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important thing is language. Make sure you phrase things in a
positive way, negative feedback often alienates people and drives them
into defensive behaviour, the opposite of what you need to solve a
communication problem. This needs practice as we normally give bad
feedback to people that make errors, rethink this habit and try to give
encouraging feedback that helps them do it better the next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get advice</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/20/how-to-get-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/20/how-to-get-advice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A key task for any co-founder is getting advice. Especially if you are
new to something it is key to ask. It is important to understand that
others have more experience in things that you will bang your head
against. Getting advice is key to a successful start and helps you keep
on track, helps you grow and helps you reposition yourself. Advice is a
key ingredient for many of the most successful entrepreneurs and not
getting advice is a silly thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does one get advice? A lot of young entrepreneurs mistake advice
with a &amp;ldquo;how-to&amp;rdquo;. Trust me, there is no how-to on being successful, there
are way too many factors that come into play and if there would be a
how-to we would drown in a flood of successful startups and would need
another word for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grew up next to a buddhist monastery and many of my fundamental world
views are based on buddhist principles like do no evil, live an
altruistic life and live what you teach. One very fundamental principle
that always stood out for me is that a student teacher relationship is
something that needs to be re-evaluated, constantly. A student should
always ask himself if the teacher is right, if the topic is relevant to
the student and if the teacher is going into the right direction from
the students point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking this principle and applying it to getting advice lead me to
always trying to get to the essence someone advises me on. I try to get
the core principle, the core idea and then evaluate how it fits into my
world view, into my bigger picture. Reevaluating advice and having a
clear idea of your core values and your core idea helps you applying
advice and still staying true to your values. Advice used as a how-to,
blindly followed and executing upon without understanding the underlying
learnings can derail perfectly good ideas and teams. Not because the one
giving advice wants to harm you but because blindly following a recipe
is rarely giving you the insights that you need to apply the recipe in
the right way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always try to understand what the key learning is and how to apply it to
your startup. Advice comes from people, often successful, from their
point of view and from their point of view in their companies. It may be
highly relevant but it is always from their angle, be aware of it and
know how to evaluate its usefulness to your startup.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>leading by example</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/14/leading-by-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/14/leading-by-example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Leadership is a tricky thing and over the years I have tried different
styles and was exposed to different styles. I have observed many every
successful people and people in high positions that lead big companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that most leaders fall into two categories. Leader by example
and leader by position. What I mean with that is people that live and
breath what they demand from their team, people that are respected for
what they know and people that don&amp;rsquo;t have to hide behind a title to be
accepted. Those leaders were generally accepted in the team they worked
and were normally not questioned or challenged by their peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading by position is a style often found in larger companies where
politics is enough to get a position and actual execution is more in the
way than a contributing factor. If the goal is lots of money then this
leading style can be highly efficient. If the goal is a functioning team
and a good work environment then this leading style is toxic. It does
not create a level of trust and you often end up with the typical management
style where &lt;em&gt;resources&lt;/em&gt; get allocated to tasks and leaders spend most of
their time in meetings discussing important things that the team then
has to &lt;em&gt;execute&lt;/em&gt; on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to lead by example you are part of and not on top of a team.
Leading by example means that you surround yourself with peers not with
underlings that do your work. I have seen many very successful people
that did exactly that, being part of a team and leading from within not
from the top.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic vs extrinsic motivation</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/13/intrinsic-vs-extrinsic-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/13/intrinsic-vs-extrinsic-motivation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have mentored at Startup Weekend Auckland last weekend and noticed an
interesting pattern. Participants that were at the weekend with the goal
to win the competition were less motivated in the teams they were in if
they thought the team is not doing well. Participants that were at the
weekend primarily to learn something and did not care too much about
winning were highly motivated and performed really well. Teams
consisting exclusively out of participants who wanted to learn were very
receptive to external input and managed to deliver a very good product.
The winning team was formed by participants that wanted to learn, they
were very motivated and executed very well as a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how come trying to win is in the way of winning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It comes down to intrinsic vs extrinsic motivation. If your motivation
is trying to achieve something real bad and your task involves
non-trivial problems, or highly creative tasks then any focus on the
goal slows you down. If the task is a highly repetitive task then
extrinsic motivation works very well. I had seen this before and
remembered the candle problem outlined here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Candle_Problem&#34; title=&#34;Wikipedia: The candle problem&#34;&gt;Wikipedia: The candle problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intrinsic motivation should always be the one that you push in your
startup. Trying to motivate you and your team by extrinsic motivators
will hinder your performance as a team and will be in your way to make
best use of your creativity. Always look for a way to push intrinsic
motivators and your productivity and creativity will rise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to end a conversation with me</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/08/how-to-end-a-conversation-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/08/how-to-end-a-conversation-with-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I get quite a few people that ask me for advice on technical co-founders
or how to find a technical person for their startup. The one sentence
that ends a conversation with me needing to urgently attend another
meeting or some other way of getting away in a polite way is the
following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know how to do idea X; I only need a technical person to build it
for me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is doomed for failure on many levels and my time is wasted trying
to point out why. If you find yourself in this situation then here are
some things to think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to train for a marathon and never wore running shoes before
you can pay a personal trainer to get you fit but paying him to run for
you will not prepare you for the marathon, never mind how good that PT
is. Building a startup is way more challenging than running a marathon
and thinking that hiring a tech guy to &amp;ldquo;just build it&amp;rdquo; is like blaming
the PT for your missing training. If you are not looking for a partner,
for someone to work with and develop something then you are missing the
point of building something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next misconception is that you think you know everything and all
that is missing is the tech. If your attitude from the get go is that
you already know everything then why bother doing it, you will not learn
anything. You will waste a whole lot of time and energy realising that you did
not know everything and that is a very frustrating realisation that will
never lead you to a successful startup. It will make you bitter and give
you the idea that building startups is a horrible thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing that will make you very unhappy is the fact that you
&amp;ldquo;only need a tech guy&amp;rdquo;. Looking for &amp;ldquo;only a tech guy&amp;rdquo; implies that you
know how to manage a tech guy. Look for a co-founder, look for someone
you can trust on a personal level and build the business with that
person. It is critical that the product vision and the technical vision
are well aligned. Even in teams that know each other very well the
product and tech teams will always challenge each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understand that your idea is only as good as the team that helps you get
there. If you think of them as underlings you will have a hard time
getting them aligned and turnover will be high. If you manage to get a
team together that is passionate about your idea, your turnover will be
low and everyone will give the best to make this idea a success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I referred you here, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that the meeting I ran away to was
fake and I hope you learned why I did it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting into habits</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/07/getting-into-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/07/getting-into-habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Habits structure your life. Knowing your habits and training new habits
can be real challenging and a lot of books have been written about how
to get into habits that help you achieve your goals. Thing is, like most
new year resolutions, it is real hard to stick to a habit and make it
stick around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have recently started playing &lt;a href=&#34;http://habitrpg.com&#34;&gt;HabitRPG&lt;/a&gt; and
challenged my partner to join me. We now battle us for points to things
like drinking enough water during the day or go running. HabitRPG is an
amazing little game that helps you gamify your habits and todos in a
really engaging way and helps you stay on top of your habits &amp;hellip; or you
run out of health points and die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those that are commandline affictionados there is a commandline
interface to HabitRPG that helps greatly in automating task completions
and tying it into a daily workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to start?</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/04/25/where-to-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/04/25/where-to-start/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I often get asked what non-technical co-founders should start
with till they have found a technical co-founder. Mostly followed by,
&amp;ldquo;where can I find a technical co-founder&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting topic as quite often I see the non-technical
co-founders seeing their role in telling a tech guy what to do who
then magically turns it into working code. Unfortunately this is not
quite how it works and as a non-technical co-founder joining a startup
without any understanding what it means to write software and to build a
startup will most probably end in tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My number one suggestion for anyone looking for a technical co-founder
is to show up for user group meetings in any programming language. It
has a whole range of positive effects, first, you normally get beer and
depending on the language even pizza. You meet a lot of quite technical
people that are all passionate enough about a programming language to
meet once a month in their spare time and talk about what they have
learned and share it with others. This means there is already a high
level of commitment to do more than a 9-5 job. Next, you get an idea
about stuff that can be done with a language or prolems people have.
Don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you don&amp;rsquo;t understand all of it, there will be at least
some things that stick and if you show up more often you will understand
more and more. Just a heads up, you will have to learn way more than you
hope about programming if you start without a lot of funding and with a
team of two or three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important part of a user group meeting is the social part.
Depending on the community this happens at the venue where the meeting
was or moves into a pub nearby. Talking to geeks and pitching your idea
to them is the most daunting thing you will ever do. If you were scared
about pitching to a VC, start by pitching to real geeks. Geeks will
either question your idea entierly or tell you all the reasons why it is
a stupid idea and can&amp;rsquo;t be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are lucky, there is one or two that will continue talking to you
past this point, if not, rethink your pitch and pick the next language
or come back for the next meeting with a better pitch. If you can
convince a developer of your idea, make sure you click on a personal
level. I will write more on how to find a good co-founder but don&amp;rsquo;t
think that you can just hire the best guy and everything will work
out. You need a partner that fully buys into your idea, not just a code
monkey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>