<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freebsd on norbu09</title>
    <link>http://lnz.me/tags/freebsd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freebsd on norbu09</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 15:27:00 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lnz.me/tags/freebsd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>laptop update</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/post/2016-09-30-laptop-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 15:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/post/2016-09-30-laptop-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lnz.me/2016/07/26/on-coming-home/&#34;&gt;Back in July I wrote&lt;/a&gt; about going back to FreeBSD and I wanted to give a quick
update on that. To sum it up, it was so painless it nearly does not warrant a
blog post. I tinkered around a bit with 10.3-RELEASE and 11-CURRENT before
stumbling over &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trueos.org/&#34;&gt;TrueOS&lt;/a&gt; the new name for PCBSD, gave
it a try and never looked back. Initially I had some trouble with my display
driver and just used the framebuffer one to have something working but TrueOS
found all hardware instantly and just made it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that work out of the box on the X1 Carbon that surprised me:
- plugging in an external projector, notoriously painful, just works
- sound
- trackpad, incl scrolling how I am used to on a mac&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I needed to fix:
- media keys for volume
- resume&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I am super happy, still need to figure out a nicer way to run the update
process from i3 as I got really used to that and seem to struggle a bit with
Lumina but happy enough to just fire up that every now and then and update from
there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The suspend works nicely but resume messes up my graphics but surprisingly I
got used to shutting down my laptop and have a few interesting side effects,
like starting with a clean slate every morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very happy that I made the switch back to FreeBSD and nothing that could make
me switch back any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on coming home</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2016/07/26/on-coming-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2016/07/26/on-coming-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first FreeBSD version was 2.2.8, for context, that was in the late 90s. I
started running FreeBSD on my desktops back then, and even managed to get it
onto a few laptops. I also build servers and firewalls and I loved the OS but
eventually caved in and switched to a Mac (a shiny 12&amp;rdquo; MacBook) around the
FreeBSD 5 days (that would have been the mid 2000s)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From really enjoying shiny GUI tools and working Wifi without patching my
kernel, did I mention suspend/resume?, I started treating my Mac more and more
like a traditional Unix machine. I went back to mutt, I never stopped using vim
and more recently even switched my IM setup over to mcabber. I work inside tmux
about 80% of my day and find it so much more productive than the shiny GUIs.
I still love a graphical browser and a few tools like zoom that are a backbone
of my remote work environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years I went from seeing the Mac scene from lacking basic tools to
having MacPorts and fink to getting a really good and current package manager
with homebrew. I saw MacOS from being a fast, pretty UI that lacked a few
things like multiple desktops to becoming pretty full featured but also less
and less transparent. It went from being a nice OS that has enough FreeBSD
under the hood to feel a bit like home but shiny to being shiny without any
sense of feeling at home. It is a dull tool I have to use very day, no more
love, no more passion, just a tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My laptop is up for renewal and I was hoping for nice new Mac hardware that has
enough power to run a full screen FreeBSD VM in a proper hypervisor and give me
good hardware with an OS I feel at home in plus an easy migration path. I tried
veertu, Parallels and VirtualBox and decided to not wait for the absurdly
secretive timeline of new hardware releases from Apple. I decided to go back to
hacking drivers if I have to and to live with broken suspend/resume. I bought a
boring Lenovo laptop and will report over the coming weeks about my adventures
home in FreeBSD land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till my new laptop gets shipped I will continue to click through the error
reports Parallels throws at me and continue to discover what FreeBSD has done
over the past 10 years and love what I am seeing so far. It&amp;rsquo;s been a
long time but it is good to be home again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>