<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">



  

<title type="text">Lenz Gschwendtner</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://lnz.me/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lnz.me/" />
<updated>2015-04-09T10:28:15+12:00</updated>
<id>http://lnz.me/</id>
<author>
  <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
  <uri>http://lnz.me/</uri>
  <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Does open source contribute to a more open society?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/does-open-source-contribute-to-a-more-open-society.html"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/does-open-source-contribute-to-a-more-open-society</id>
  <updated>2015-04-09 10:24:34 +1200</updated>
  <published>2015-04-09T00:00:00+12:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" /><category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#iwantmyname" term="iwantmyname" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;Linking to a post I wrote for the iwantmyname blog a few days ago in the
leadup for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opensourceopensociety.com/&quot;&gt;OS//OS&lt;/a&gt; - a
conference about open source and open society.&lt;/p&gt;

  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/does-open-source-contribute-to-a-more-open-society/&quot;&gt;Does open source contribute to a more open society?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on April 09, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[a new view]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lnz.me/a-new-view/"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/a-new-view</id>
  <updated>2015-03-09 20:03:01 +1300</updated>
  <published>2015-03-09T00:00:00+13:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" /><category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#life" term="life" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;We are starting a new experiment in our life, it is called “project
mountain retreat”. The back story to this experiment is that Manu, 
ever since we first were in St Arnaud and looked at Lake Rotoiti, loved
this place and it felt very much at home for me right away. It took us
years to come back to this place but now we plan to stay a bit longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the Europe experiment showed we really don’t enjoy the city life for
much more than a couple of days, after that we really like the calm and
quiet of more remote places. When we took out the lease at our current
place we knew it would only be for a few months and planned to build a
tiny house and put it on the south island and go between there and
Wellington to have the best of both worlds. Looking for places we found
a cute little mountain retreat that offered all we wanted but was
already built. Not a tiny house, and that plan is really only postponed
a bit, but a little hut in the mountains, just outside of St Arnaud. It
is calm and far away and still close enough to Wellington that we can
enjoy the city life for a couple of days a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will report here on progress and learnings from this experiment. It feels
like going on an adventure and a bit like getting back some of the things
I started missing, like actual winters and ski fields around the corner,
but still have the sandy beaches of the Able Tasman region on our door step.&lt;/p&gt;


  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/a-new-view/&quot;&gt;a new view&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on March 09, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The chilling effect of tech law]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/business/news/article.cfm?c_id=3&objectid=11409067"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/miserable-state-of-tech-law-in-nz</id>
  <updated>2015-02-28</updated>
  <published>2015-02-28T00:00:00+13:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;Two years ago I was part of a bunch of people who put in a submission on
the Telecommunications (Interception Capability and Security) Bill. &lt;a href=&quot;http://dave.moskovitz.co.nz/2013/08/13/tics-bill-submission/&quot;&gt;Dave
wrote about it here: http://dave.moskovitz.co.nz/2013/08/13/tics-bill-submission/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juha Saarinen posted this article on the Herald and it is really not
helping to turn around and say “we told you so”, what we actually need
is politicians to get off their arrogant attitude and actually listen to
the tech community. We are a nice bunch and totally approachable but if
we get pissed off too much we’ll just move our companies into countries
that have more predictable laws and politicians that are less
ill informed than ours. And know what? there may even be a significant
tax advantage in doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can, however, keep turning a blind eye on the increasingly warm
summers that dry out our country and hope that dairy is the future.&lt;/p&gt;

  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/miserable-state-of-tech-law-in-nz/&quot;&gt;The chilling effect of tech law&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on February 28, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Burnout and how to see it]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lnz.me/articles/burnout-and-how-to-see-it/"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/burnout-and-how-to-see-it</id>
  <updated>2015-02-02</updated>
  <published>2015-02-02T00:00:00+13:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;I read Derek Sivers post &lt;a href=&quot;http://sivers.org/bad&quot;&gt;Getting out of a bad
place&lt;/a&gt; today and it made me clean up my blog,
re-launch it, collect a few old posts I had scattered around and release
a post that I, myself, had only shared privately so far. It is about my
history with work-till-you-drop and my history with a mind that is
driven to continue well past the point where it is productive or
healthy. I hope it is a post that makes you think if you are in a
similar situation or, even more important, helps you realise you are in
a bad place. A friend I shared this post with recently wrote to me a few
months after meeting him and told me that this made him realise that he
was way down that track already without seeing it. He made drastic
changes to his life and is a way happier person now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-burnout&quot;&gt;About burnout&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my live I have worked quite a lot so far. Many would say I have also
achieved a lot but funny enough for me that never felt that way. I had
my first burnout age 30. I hit rock bottom, knew I had to change
something and decided to kill my career and start from scratch. I
thought that at that time I had learned enough to start again, do
something else and just spend my time enjoying live again. Many who
knew me at that time did not notice that I was a wrack, that I had
massive issues with depression and was just focusing on external
problems to not having to deal with myself. It was a pretty dark time
for me even though my career was going well and the company I worked for
was pretty successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved on, recovered, bootstrapped my live in a new country, working
for someone else and just enjoyed life. Thing is, it was actually quite
boring so I started working on a little side project. That side project
turned into a company, that company needed money so I started another
company to finance the first and a few years down the road I noticed
that I had fallen into the same trap I was in before. This time I knew a
bit more and maybe saw my situation in a different light. I knew that I
had to change something but I also knew that I had amazing teams to
rely on and the support from my partner who is never tired to look after
me. She already supported me through my first melt down and not
only helped me build our companies but also always looked after me never
mind which state I was in. I know today that thanks to the people around
me I can get back on my feet, do less, focus on myself more and still
contribute to my companies in a meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick side story, I was in Scotland recently and we did a bit of
hiking. I have not done any hiking in anger in a long time and we
decided to hike up Ben Nevis, the highest mountain in the UK. It is a 4h
hike up and a 3h hike down over a pretty shitty path with large boulders
and it really is not that dramatic but in my physical condition it was
way too much for me. Now, my body told me about half way up that this is
not going to work but my mind totally did not accept that. I was up
there, it was amazing, after I got up from that big bolder I was lying
on and slept for an hour, then tried to eat some which I nearly vomited
right away - I did not listen to my body. My fear of being inferior and
me being determined to get up there did serious harm to my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back at my downward spiral experiences I see many analogies, I
did not listen to my body and that took its toll. This time round I got
away without depressions, maybe because I know in the meantime how to
deal with them, maybe because I already suffered from massive anxiety
and claustrophobia. It was not a pretty time and I hope that anyone who
goes through a time like this has a strong partner at his side that
gives them the support to pull themselves out of that again. I have that
strong partner at my side and am very lucky that I managed, thanks to
her, to pull myself out again and listen to my body more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that I’ll find my balance at some stage, I certainly know the
signs and know how it feels when I am there but hopefully I will not
forget to listen to my body. I can really only highly urge everyone who
works in a fast paced company to sit back every now and then, reflect
and check if what you do is healthy. Pace is not everything, you only
got this one live and the mad rush of fast growing companies is amazing
but you need to know when to change your mode of running it and when to
change your pace. Running a company is a long term thing and it is only
rewarding if you are on that peak and enjoy the view without that
desire to vomit and sleep or to just hope that a helicopter comes around
the corner to pick you up.&lt;/p&gt;


  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/burnout-and-how-to-see-it/&quot;&gt;Burnout and how to see it&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on February 02, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Subdomain rot and the security implications]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2014/10/sub-domain-rot.html"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/sub-domain-rot</id>
  <updated>2014-10-23</updated>
  <published>2014-10-23T00:00:00+13:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;A post I wrote for the iwantmyname blog about sub domains and how not
cleaning them up every now and then can lead to unexpected behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;


  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/sub-domain-rot/&quot;&gt;Subdomain rot and the security implications&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on October 23, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The difference between 4hww and me]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lnz.me/articles/the-difference-between-4hww-and-me/"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/the-difference-between-4hww-and-me</id>
  <updated>2014-08-21</updated>
  <published>2014-08-21T00:00:00+12:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;I attended a 4 hour work week meetup in Berlin yesterday and noticed one big
difference between me and many that were there. Tim Ferris, the author or 4
hour work week, starts from the point of view that work is something that is
not fun and in order to “live” you need to work as little as possible so you
can enjoy your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, this is where I would argue that I haven’t worked in a long time as
everything I do are things I actually enjoy doing. Even the things I
don’t like as a task I tend to see as things that get me closer to the
things I like and so they don’t seem to bother me at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living a happy life to me is not sitting at a beach all day, I get bored
after a few hours and really want to get something done after that. I really
enjoy times where I just hang out with people and talk but even that is
time where I learn, where I do something I like that ultimately adds
to my personal development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four hours of work a week seems way too much or too little to me, I
really prefer doing stuff I like without any time restriction.&lt;/p&gt;

  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/the-difference-between-4hww-and-me/&quot;&gt;The difference between 4hww and me&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on August 21, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[On hiring and hierarchy]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2014/05/culture-at-iwmn-part-three.html"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/culture-at-iwmn-part-three</id>
  <updated>2014-05-07</updated>
  <published>2014-08-19T00:00:00+12:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;A post I wrote for the iwantmyname blog about culture and how we hire people&lt;/p&gt;


  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/culture-at-iwmn-part-three/&quot;&gt;On hiring and hierarchy&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on August 19, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Berlin]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lnz.me/articles/berlin/"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/berlin</id>
  <updated>2014-08-07</updated>
  <published>2014-08-07T00:00:00+12:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;Since a while we live in Berlin for a change. It is really interesting
to see how much New Zealand changed me and to see how different things
look to me now, that I have distance to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most obvious thing to me is that there is this interesting split
between expats that are here to enjoy living in the startup capital of
Europe and the Germans that always find something that is bothering
them, something they can complain about, something that someone needs to
change. The observation for me is that Germans in Germany are happy to
make some else responsible for their current situation whereas those who
come here just try to get stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may be a bigger thought and because of the comparably young age of
New Zealand most Kiwis needed to get stuff done, complaining did not get
you anywhere. Obviously there are awesome people here in Germany that
get stuff done, don’t blame any higher instance for their current
situation and there are Kiwis that complain bitterly about things, it is
more the general mood, the general way of how the majority thinks and
represents itself to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, summer is awesome and there are plenty of positive people around me,
just most of them speak English … like me.&lt;/p&gt;

  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/berlin/&quot;&gt;Berlin&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on August 07, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The "work-from-anywhere experiment"]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2014/05/culture-at-iwmn-part-two.html"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/culture-at-iwmn-part-two</id>
  <updated>2014-05-07</updated>
  <published>2014-05-22T00:00:00+12:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;A post I wrote for the iwantmyname blog about culture and our work place policy.&lt;/p&gt;


  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/culture-at-iwmn-part-two/&quot;&gt;The "work-from-anywhere experiment"&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on May 22, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The "one salary experiment"]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2014/05/culture-at-iwmn-part-one.html"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/culture-at-iwmn-part-one</id>
  <updated>2014-05-07</updated>
  <published>2014-05-07T00:00:00+12:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;A post I wrote for the iwantmyname blog about culture and how we decide on who gets how much.&lt;/p&gt;

  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/culture-at-iwmn-part-one/&quot;&gt;The "one salary experiment"&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on May 07, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why ALIAS-type DNS Records Break The Internet]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2014/01/why-alias-type-records-break-the-internet.html"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/why-alias-type-records-break-the-internet</id>
  <updated>2014-01-07</updated>
  <published>2014-01-07T00:00:00+13:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;A post I wrote for the iwantmyname blog about ALIAS DNS records and why they break the internet.&lt;/p&gt;


  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/why-alias-type-records-break-the-internet/&quot;&gt;Why ALIAS-type DNS Records Break The Internet&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on January 07, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[upcoming Startup Weekends]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lnz.me/articles/upcoming-startup-weekends/"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/upcoming-startup-weekends</id>
  <updated>2013-06-05</updated>
  <published>2013-06-05T00:00:00+12:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" /><category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#startup" term="startup" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;There are two Startup Weekends coming up in Hawkes Bay and Taurange.
Startup Weekends are a perfect opportunity to learn how to transform an
idea to a MVP, a minimal viable product. Startup Weekends are a crash
course in entrepreneurschip over a weekend in a sheltered environment
and with near to no financial implications. The costs, in fact, are
often not even covering the food and drinks provided during the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upcoming startup weekends in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://hawkesbay.startupweekend.org/&quot;&gt;Hawkes Bay&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://tauranga.startupweekend.org/&quot;&gt;Tauranga&lt;/a&gt; are on
the weekend of the 28th of June and following weekend of the 5th of July
respectively. Make sure you show up at one of them if you are in the
region and plan to push your idea to the next stage. We have world class
mentors at both events and we will definitely have a lot of fun and
learn a lot over these two weekends.&lt;/p&gt;


  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/upcoming-startup-weekends/&quot;&gt;upcoming Startup Weekends&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on June 05, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Communication]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lnz.me/articles/communication/"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/communication</id>
  <updated>2013-05-21</updated>
  <published>2013-05-21T00:00:00+12:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" /><category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#startup" term="startup" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;When starting a company there is a lot of stuff that needs to be looked
at. There are lots of things that need your attention and many things
will not be talked about because there is simply no time for it. This can
very easily lead to a habit of not communicating with everyone in the
team. Another frequent problem is that from your own point of view a lot
of things are very obvious and you just can’t understand how someone in
your team can’t see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If left untreated this will become a big ugly scar and can break
successful teams over time. Communication is a tricky thing, it needs a
lot of attention to detail and needs a lot of time to get right. Every
new addition to your team will change communication and will need new
ways of communication. The one thing that is the most tricky is
understanding and always coming back to the fact that we are all human,
we make errors and it is often hard to talk with someone who you think
is in the wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always try to address communication issues by asking myself what can I
do to fix this, what can I do to address a lack of communication. I
always try to be the one initiating the conversation again after
something went wrong or something did not work out the way we planned.
Communication is key, keep it up, talk to each other, always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important thing is language. Make sure you phrase things in a
positive way, negative feedback often alienates people and drives them
into defensive behaviour, the opposite of what you need to solve a
communication problem. This needs practice as we normally give bad
feedback to people that make errors, rethink this habit and try to give
encouraging feedback that helps them do it better the next time.&lt;/p&gt;

  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/communication/&quot;&gt;Communication&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on May 21, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to get advice]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lnz.me/articles/how-to-get-advice/"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/how-to-get-advice</id>
  <updated>2013-05-20</updated>
  <published>2013-05-20T00:00:00+12:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" /><category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#startup" term="startup" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;A key task for any co-founder is getting advice. Especially if you are
new to something it is key to ask. It is important to understand that
others have more experience in things that you will bang your head
against. Getting advice is key to a successful start and helps you keep
on track, helps you grow and helps you reposition yourself. Advice is a
key ingredient for many of the most successful entrepreneurs and not
getting advice is a silly thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does one get advice? A lot of young entrepreneurs mistake advice
with a “how-to”. Trust me, there is no how-to on being successful, there
are way too many factors that come into play and if there would be a
how-to we would drown in a flood of successful startups and would need
another word for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grew up next to a buddhist monastery and many of my fundamental world
views are based on buddhist principles like do no evil, live an
altruistic life and live what you teach. One very fundamental principle
that always stood out for me is that a student teacher relationship is
something that needs to be re-evaluated, constantly. A student should
always ask himself if the teacher is right, if the topic is relevant to
the student and if the teacher is going into the right direction from
the students point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking this principle and applying it to getting advice lead me to
always trying to get to the essence someone advises me on. I try to get
the core principle, the core idea and then evaluate how it fits into my
world view, into my bigger picture. Reevaluating advice and having a
clear idea of your core values and your core idea helps you applying
advice and still staying true to your values. Advice used as a how-to,
blindly followed and executing upon without understanding the underlying
learnings can derail perfectly good ideas and teams. Not because the one
giving advice wants to harm you but because blindly following a recipe
is rarely giving you the insights that you need to apply the recipe in
the right way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always try to understand what the key learning is and how to apply it to
your startup. Advice comes from people, often successful, from their
point of view and from their point of view in their companies. It may be
highly relevant but it is always from their angle, be aware of it and
know how to evaluate its usefulness to your startup.&lt;/p&gt;

  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/how-to-get-advice/&quot;&gt;How to get advice&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on May 20, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[leading by example]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lnz.me/articles/leading-by-example/"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/leading-by-example</id>
  <updated>2013-05-14</updated>
  <published>2013-05-14T00:00:00+12:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" /><category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#startup" term="startup" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;Leadership is a tricky thing and over the years I have tried different
styles and was exposed to different styles. I have observed many every
successful people and people in high positions that lead big companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that most leaders fall into two categories. Leader by example
and leader by position. What I mean with that is people that live and
breath what they demand from their team, people that are respected for
what they know and people that don’t have to hide behind a title to be
accepted. Those leaders were generally accepted in the team they worked
and were normally not questioned or challenged by their peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading by position is a style often found in larger companies where
politics is enough to get a position and actual execution is more in the
way than a contributing factor. If the goal is lots of money then this
leading style can be highly efficient. If the goal is a functioning team
and a good work environment then this leading style is toxic. It does
not create a level of trust and you often end up with the typical management
style where &lt;em&gt;resources&lt;/em&gt; get allocated to tasks and leaders spend most of
their time in meetings discussing important things that the team then
has to &lt;em&gt;execute&lt;/em&gt; on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to lead by example you are part of and not on top of a team.
Leading by example means that you surround yourself with peers not with
underlings that do your work. I have seen many very successful people
that did exactly that, being part of a team and leading from within not
from the top.&lt;/p&gt;

  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/leading-by-example/&quot;&gt;leading by example&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on May 14, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intrinsic vs extrinsic motivation]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lnz.me/articles/intrinsic-vs-extrinsic-motivation/"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/intrinsic-vs-extrinsic-motivation</id>
  <updated>2013-05-13</updated>
  <published>2013-05-13T00:00:00+12:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" /><category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#startup" term="startup" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;I have mentored at Startup Weekend Auckland last weekend and noticed an
interesting pattern. Participants that were at the weekend with the goal
to win the competition were less motivated in the teams they were in if
they thought the team is not doing well. Participants that were at the
weekend primarily to learn something and did not care too much about
winning were highly motivated and performed really well. Teams
consisting exclusively out of participants who wanted to learn were very
receptive to external input and managed to deliver a very good product.
The winning team was formed by participants that wanted to learn, they
were very motivated and executed very well as a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how come trying to win is in the way of winning? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It comes down to intrinsic vs extrinsic motivation. If your motivation
is trying to achieve something real bad and your task involves
non-trivial problems, or highly creative tasks then any focus on the
goal slows you down. If the task is a highly repetitive task then
extrinsic motivation works very well. I had seen this before and
remembered the candle problem outlined here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Candle_Problem (Wikipedia: The candle problem)&quot;&gt;Wikipedia: The candle problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intrinsic motivation should always be the one that you push in your
startup. Trying to motivate you and your team by extrinsic motivators
will hinder your performance as a team and will be in your way to make
best use of your creativity. Always look for a way to push intrinsic
motivators and your productivity and creativity will rise.&lt;/p&gt;


  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/intrinsic-vs-extrinsic-motivation/&quot;&gt;Intrinsic vs extrinsic motivation&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on May 13, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to end a conversation with me]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lnz.me/articles/how-to-end-a-conversation-with-me/"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/how-to-end-a-conversation-with-me</id>
  <updated>2013-05-08</updated>
  <published>2013-05-08T00:00:00+12:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" /><category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#startup" term="startup" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;I get quite a few people that ask me for advice on technical co-founders
or how to find a technical person for their startup. The one sentence
that ends a conversation with me needing to urgently attend another
meeting or some other way of getting away in a polite way is the
following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I know how to do idea X; I only need a technical person to build it
for me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is doomed for failure on many levels and my time is wasted trying
to point out why. If you find yourself in this situation then here are
some things to think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to train for a marathon and never wore running shoes before
you can pay a personal trainer to get you fit but paying him to run for
you will not prepare you for the marathon, never mind how good that PT
is. Building a startup is way more challenging than running a marathon
and thinking that hiring a tech guy to “just build it” is like blaming
the PT for your missing training. If you are not looking for a partner,
for someone to work with and develop something then you are missing the
point of building something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next misconception is that you think you know everything and all
that is missing is the tech. If your attitude from the get go is that
you already know everything then why bother doing it, you will not learn
anything. You will waste a whole lot of time and energy realising that you did
not know everything and that is a very frustrating realisation that will
never lead you to a successful startup. It will make you bitter and give
you the idea that building startups is a horrible thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing that will make you very unhappy is the fact that you
“only need a tech guy”. Looking for “only a tech guy” implies that you
know how to manage a tech guy. Look for a co-founder, look for someone
you can trust on a personal level and build the business with that
person. It is critical that the product vision and the technical vision
are well aligned. Even in teams that know each other very well the
product and tech teams will always challenge each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understand that your idea is only as good as the team that helps you get
there. If you think of them as underlings you will have a hard time
getting them aligned and turnover will be high. If you manage to get a
team together that is passionate about your idea, your turnover will be
low and everyone will give the best to make this idea a success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I referred you here, you’ll know that the meeting I ran away to was
fake and I hope you learned why I did it.&lt;/p&gt;


  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/how-to-end-a-conversation-with-me/&quot;&gt;How to end a conversation with me&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on May 08, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting into habits]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lnz.me/articles/getting-into-habits/"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/getting-into-habits</id>
  <updated>2013-05-07</updated>
  <published>2013-05-07T00:00:00+12:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" /><category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#startup" term="startup" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;Habits structure your life. Knowing your habits and training new habits
can be real challenging and a lot of books have been written about how
to get into habits that help you achieve your goals. Thing is, like most
new year resolutions, it is real hard to stick to a habit and make it
stick around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have recently started playing &lt;a href=&quot;http://habitrpg.com&quot;&gt;HabitRPG&lt;/a&gt; and
challenged my partner to join me. We now battle us for points to things
like drinking enough water during the day or go running. HabitRPG is an
amazing little game that helps you gamify your habits and todos in a
really engaging way and helps you stay on top of your habits … or you
run out of health points and die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those that are commandline affictionados there is a commandline
interface to HabitRPG that helps greatly in automating task completions
and tying it into a daily workflow.&lt;/p&gt;


  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/getting-into-habits/&quot;&gt;Getting into habits&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on May 07, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where to start?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lnz.me/articles/where-to-start/"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/where-to-start</id>
  <updated>2013-04-25</updated>
  <published>2013-04-25T00:00:00+12:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" /><category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#startup" term="startup" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;I often get asked what non-technical co-founders should start
with till they have found a technical co-founder. Mostly followed by,
“where can I find a technical co-founder”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting topic as quite often I see the non-technical
co-founders seeing their role in telling a tech guy what to do who
then magically turns it into working code. Unfortunately this is not
quite how it works and as a non-technical co-founder joining a startup
without any understanding what it means to write software and to build a
startup will most probably end in tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My number one suggestion for anyone looking for a technical co-founder
is to show up for user group meetings in any programming language. It
has a whole range of positive effects, first, you normally get beer and
depending on the language even pizza. You meet a lot of quite technical
people that are all passionate enough about a programming language to
meet once a month in their spare time and talk about what they have
learned and share it with others. This means there is already a high
level of commitment to do more than a 9-5 job. Next, you get an idea
about stuff that can be done with a language or prolems people have.
Don’t worry if you don’t understand all of it, there will be at least
some things that stick and if you show up more often you will understand
more and more. Just a heads up, you will have to learn way more than you
hope about programming if you start without a lot of funding and with a
team of two or three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important part of a user group meeting is the social part.
Depending on the community this happens at the venue where the meeting
was or moves into a pub nearby. Talking to geeks and pitching your idea
to them is the most daunting thing you will ever do. If you were scared
about pitching to a VC, start by pitching to real geeks. Geeks will
either question your idea entierly or tell you all the reasons why it is
a stupid idea and can’t be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are lucky, there is one or two that will continue talking to you
past this point, if not, rethink your pitch and pick the next language
or come back for the next meeting with a better pitch. If you can
convince a developer of your idea, make sure you click on a personal
level. I will write more on how to find a good co-founder but don’t
think that you can just hire the best guy and everything will work
out. You need a partner that fully buys into your idea, not just a code
monkey.&lt;/p&gt;

  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/where-to-start/&quot;&gt;Where to start?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on April 25, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Care For Dynamic DNS (DDNS) Updates?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2012/03/ddns-dynamic-dns-service-on-your-own-domain.html"/>
  <id>http://lnz.me/articles/ddns-dynamic-dns-service-on-your-own-domain</id>
  <updated>2014-03-01</updated>
  <published>2012-03-01T00:00:00+13:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lenz Gschwendtner</name>
    <uri>http://lnz.me</uri>
    <email>mail@norbu09.org</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="http://lnz.me/tags/#post" term="post" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;A post I wrote for the iwantmyname blog about dynamic DNS updates at iwantmyname.&lt;/p&gt;


  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me/articles/ddns-dynamic-dns-service-on-your-own-domain/&quot;&gt;Care For Dynamic DNS (DDNS) Updates?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lenz Gschwendtner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnz.me&quot;&gt;Lenz Gschwendtner&lt;/a&gt; on March 01, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>
