<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on norbu09</title>
    <link>http://lnz.me/tags/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on norbu09</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lnz.me/tags/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About perception</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2017/01/17/about-perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2017/01/17/about-perception/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a post about perception and my &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t complain but fix&amp;rdquo; policy for this year over at the iwantmyname blog. Head over to the iwantmyname blog and tweet your comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>founder.chat - growing a community</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2016/01/11/founder-dot-chat-growing-a-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2016/01/11/founder-dot-chat-growing-a-community/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Thursday, 14th January 2016, 5:30 at Bridge Street
I am passionate about community and passionate about empowering people to realise their ideas, as opposed to just talking about them. I am also keen to bring together people so that they can help each other.
New year, new challenge. My personal challenge for this year is to build a robust and well connected entrepreneurial fabric in Nelson and create a blueprint for regions outside the major centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Entrepreneurship Week</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/11/18/global-entrepreneurship-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/11/18/global-entrepreneurship-week/</guid>
      <description>I care about entrepreneurship because I believe in the power of collaboration and the power of people working together for fun and profit, quite literally. I see entrepreneurship as a way to create resilient communities that address problems by working together, by building companies, by creating work for others and by investing back into the community. Entrepreneurs are people that have a vision and are crazy enough to follow that vision, passionate enough to infect others with their idea and make them form a team around a common interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview for #TGASW15</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/10/22/interview-for-number-tgasw15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/10/22/interview-for-number-tgasw15/</guid>
      <description>I gave an interview about Startup Weekends and what draws me to them. Read it on the Venture Centre blog and tweet your comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lego for grownups</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/10/12/lego-for-grownups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/10/12/lego-for-grownups/</guid>
      <description>When I think about building software I try to see where we need to end up in order to help the customer right now and then work backwards from there. Because I am really bad at knowing what customers want I mock up something that is good enough to get feedback and then morph it into working code and then robust infrastructure. At iwantmyname I have pushed for this since we started and for the most part we succeeded till we tried to grow up and &amp;ldquo;clean up&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;do things properly&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The developers dilemma</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/07/07/the-developers-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/07/07/the-developers-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>Writing software is an interesting process. It transforms abstract concepts, feature requests, vague ideas into something people can interact with. It is a modern way of making ideas real, tangible, visible and hopefully usable. This process is a strange mixture of operating within tight constraints and at the same time being highly creative.
Developers come in many flavours, just like traditional crafts men, they may have studied for many years or just picked up an editor and started mucking around in someone else&amp;rsquo;s code till they felt comfortable enough to write their own code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>os//os impressions</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/04/20/os-slash-slash-os-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/04/20/os-slash-slash-os-impressions/</guid>
      <description>Last week I attended an interesting conference called open source//open society that brought together an interesting cross section of geekdom that I have not seen at a conference before. I had discussions ranging from editor flame wars via &amp;ldquo;the open source model&amp;rdquo; to tiny houses and earthships. The most interesting in my view was the high diversity of skills in the room that made for extremely interesting discussions.
It also helped me spell out and phrase what for me open source really means and what the essence of the open source movement is in my view so I wanted to share it and write it down for future reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a new view</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/03/09/a-new-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/03/09/a-new-view/</guid>
      <description>We are starting a new experiment in our life, it is called &amp;ldquo;project mountain retreat&amp;rdquo;. The back story to this experiment is that Manu, ever since we first were in St Arnaud and looked at Lake Rotoiti, loved this place and it felt very much at home for me right away. It took us years to come back to this place but now we plan to stay a bit longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burnout and how to see it</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2015/02/02/burnout-and-how-to-see-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2015/02/02/burnout-and-how-to-see-it/</guid>
      <description>I read Derek Sivers post Getting out of a bad place today and it made me clean up my blog, re-launch it, collect a few old posts I had scattered around and release a post that I, myself, had only shared privately so far. It is about my history with work-till-you-drop and my history with a mind that is driven to continue well past the point where it is productive or healthy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The difference between 4hww and me</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2014/08/21/the-difference-between-4hww-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2014/08/21/the-difference-between-4hww-and-me/</guid>
      <description>I attended a 4 hour work week meetup in Berlin yesterday and noticed one big difference between me and many that were there. Tim Ferris, the author or 4 hour work week, starts from the point of view that work is something that is not fun and in order to &amp;ldquo;live&amp;rdquo; you need to work as little as possible so you can enjoy your life.
Now, this is where I would argue that I haven&amp;rsquo;t worked in a long time as everything I do are things I actually enjoy doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2014/08/07/berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2014/08/07/berlin/</guid>
      <description>Since a while we live in Berlin for a change. It is really interesting to see how much New Zealand changed me and to see how different things look to me now, that I have distance to them.
The most obvious thing to me is that there is this interesting split between expats that are here to enjoy living in the startup capital of Europe and the Germans that always find something that is bothering them, something they can complain about, something that someone needs to change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>upcoming Startup Weekends</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/06/05/upcoming-startup-weekends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/06/05/upcoming-startup-weekends/</guid>
      <description>There are two Startup Weekends coming up in Hawkes Bay and Taurange. Startup Weekends are a perfect opportunity to learn how to transform an idea to a MVP, a minimal viable product. Startup Weekends are a crash course in entrepreneurschip over a weekend in a sheltered environment and with near to no financial implications. The costs, in fact, are often not even covering the food and drinks provided during the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/21/communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/21/communication/</guid>
      <description>When starting a company there is a lot of stuff that needs to be looked at. There are lots of things that need your attention and many things will not be talked about because there is simply no time for it. This can very easily lead to a habit of not communicating with everyone in the team. Another frequent problem is that from your own point of view a lot of things are very obvious and you just can&amp;rsquo;t understand how someone in your team can&amp;rsquo;t see it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get advice</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/20/how-to-get-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/20/how-to-get-advice/</guid>
      <description>A key task for any co-founder is getting advice. Especially if you are new to something it is key to ask. It is important to understand that others have more experience in things that you will bang your head against. Getting advice is key to a successful start and helps you keep on track, helps you grow and helps you reposition yourself. Advice is a key ingredient for many of the most successful entrepreneurs and not getting advice is a silly thing to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>leading by example</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/14/leading-by-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/14/leading-by-example/</guid>
      <description>Leadership is a tricky thing and over the years I have tried different styles and was exposed to different styles. I have observed many every successful people and people in high positions that lead big companies.
I found that most leaders fall into two categories. Leader by example and leader by position. What I mean with that is people that live and breath what they demand from their team, people that are respected for what they know and people that don&amp;rsquo;t have to hide behind a title to be accepted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic vs extrinsic motivation</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/13/intrinsic-vs-extrinsic-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/13/intrinsic-vs-extrinsic-motivation/</guid>
      <description>I have mentored at Startup Weekend Auckland last weekend and noticed an interesting pattern. Participants that were at the weekend with the goal to win the competition were less motivated in the teams they were in if they thought the team is not doing well. Participants that were at the weekend primarily to learn something and did not care too much about winning were highly motivated and performed really well. Teams consisting exclusively out of participants who wanted to learn were very receptive to external input and managed to deliver a very good product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to end a conversation with me</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/08/how-to-end-a-conversation-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/08/how-to-end-a-conversation-with-me/</guid>
      <description>I get quite a few people that ask me for advice on technical co-founders or how to find a technical person for their startup. The one sentence that ends a conversation with me needing to urgently attend another meeting or some other way of getting away in a polite way is the following:
&amp;ldquo;I know how to do idea X; I only need a technical person to build it for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting into habits</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/05/07/getting-into-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/05/07/getting-into-habits/</guid>
      <description>Habits structure your life. Knowing your habits and training new habits can be real challenging and a lot of books have been written about how to get into habits that help you achieve your goals. Thing is, like most new year resolutions, it is real hard to stick to a habit and make it stick around.
I have recently started playing HabitRPG and challenged my partner to join me. We now battle us for points to things like drinking enough water during the day or go running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to start?</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2013/04/25/where-to-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2013/04/25/where-to-start/</guid>
      <description>I often get asked what non-technical co-founders should start with till they have found a technical co-founder. Mostly followed by, &amp;ldquo;where can I find a technical co-founder&amp;rdquo;.
This is an interesting topic as quite often I see the non-technical co-founders seeing their role in telling a tech guy what to do who then magically turns it into working code. Unfortunately this is not quite how it works and as a non-technical co-founder joining a startup without any understanding what it means to write software and to build a startup will most probably end in tears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH tunnel script(2)</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2010/11/05/ssh-tunnel-script2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2010/11/05/ssh-tunnel-script2/</guid>
      <description>SSH tunnel script(2) I work quite a bit with daemons on remote hosts that are normally not directly listening to the public internet. I use SSH tunnels a lot and had previously used a simplistic script to deal with it.
I got tired of having to reconnect SSH tunnels when I changed environments and wanted autossh to handle the connections. I hacked around a bit with a shell script and then came up with his perl version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InternetNZ&#39;s missed opportunity</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2010/07/27/internetnzs-missed-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2010/07/27/internetnzs-missed-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>InternetNZ&amp;rsquo;s missed opportunity Open and uncapturable is the mission of InternetNZ and the promise to push for access to the internet for everyone. This is what we as a incorporated society stand for and what we try to push. We, all the members of InternetNZ.
Yesterday at 10:00 AM the internet saw the first ever dedicated indigenous script going online in the form of the Maori macron implementation in the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>slides from Web Meetup</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2010/07/15/slides-from-web-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2010/07/15/slides-from-web-meetup/</guid>
      <description>slides from Web Meetup
The slides from my short talk at the Wellington Web Meetup about Wellingtons worst User experience. The challenge was to describe the worst user experience in Wellington in 2 min min 5 min max.
Here are my slides:
Url uxView more presentations from Lenz Gschwendtner. and here is a direct link to the PDF: PDF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lean prototyping stack</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2010/05/25/lean-prototyping-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2010/05/25/lean-prototyping-stack/</guid>
      <description>lean prototyping stack For my new startup I play with a lean prototyping stack that will enable me to prototype and evaluate ideas really fast and test on the market. The idea is to bump out a new idea, prove it and if it works scale it further. In order to not having to rewrite the entire app once it is clear that the idea is worth pushing I tried to come up with a nice stack that enables me to prototype fast and scale if I have to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>slides from mojolicious talk</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2010/05/12/slides-from-mojolicious-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2010/05/12/slides-from-mojolicious-talk/</guid>
      <description>slides from mojolicious talk The slides from my talk about mojolicious at perlmongers Wellington yesterday are on slideshare and can be downloaded below in PDF.
MojoliciousView more presentations from Lenz Gschwendtner. and the PDF version:
mojo.pdf</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>customer uses proposal as spec</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2010/05/07/customer-uses-proposal-as-spec/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2010/05/07/customer-uses-proposal-as-spec/</guid>
      <description>customer uses proposal as spec One of the joys of working as a contractor is quoting for projects that possibly become a real project some when. The joys of a contractor quoting to a larger company (at least by New Zealand standards) is that the decision trees are so arbitrary and long that it might take ages to get one of those projects. In the meantime you hang in limbo - not too sure if you should take on another project or not as that bigger one could still come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>real geeks die early</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2010/05/05/every-once-in-a-while/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2010/05/05/every-once-in-a-while/</guid>
      <description>real geeks die early every once in a while i stumble upon an article from someone pointing out the dangers we geeks live in in terms of unhealthy work hours and our very own unhealthy mind set.
I am a developer for profit since the late 90s and a team lead since the early 2000s. i&amp;rsquo;ve seen a fair amount of problems and have done my fair share of work during nights, weekends and my holidays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ignite wellington talk</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2010/04/06/ignite-wellington-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2010/04/06/ignite-wellington-talk/</guid>
      <description>ignite wellington talk the slides and the video from my ignite wellington talk are finally online. i took part in the first ignite event in wellington which was part of the global ignite week. my talk about &amp;ldquo;realising ideas&amp;rdquo; was quite a success and i got a lot of positive feedback. in case you missed it - here is it:

and the slides on slideshare:
realising ideasView more presentations from Lenz Gschwendtner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>testing buzz ...</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2010/02/10/testing-buzz-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2010/02/10/testing-buzz-.../</guid>
      <description>testing buzz &amp;hellip; as buzz is only available via my iPhone so far i tried to figure out from the API docs and the mailinglist how to make it all work. i hope i have all the right headers in place and google actually knows that this blog belongs to my shiny google profile and all.
if all goes well this post will trigger a new entry in my buzz &amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>test driven monitoring</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2010/02/09/test-driven-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2010/02/09/test-driven-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>test driven monitoring the slides from my talk at perlmongers Wellington are up on slideshare. the talk was about how much monitoring systems suck and how to make it better. test driven monitoring is just around the corner, i only have to bump out some more base libraries but basic monitoring and notification works already. the code for the project is on github - check it out and contribute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>slides from LCA talk</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2010/01/19/slides-from-lca-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2010/01/19/slides-from-lca-talk/</guid>
      <description>MPI, Erlang and the web The slides from my talk at LCA2010 in Wellington about parallel programming and why it matters for internet infrastructures are now up on slideshare
MPI, Erlang and the webView more documents from Lenz Gschwendtner. And a direct link to the PDF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 new destination markets in some months</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2010/01/15/3-new-destination-markets-in-some-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2010/01/15/3-new-destination-markets-in-some-weeks/</guid>
      <description>Three new destination markets in some months It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit of a busy time lately as we launched three new platforms in the last time and that brought with it a lot of challenges. Fortunately it also pushed me to complete our migration to our new backend which is now entirely message driven and based only on the finest stuff one finds in the moment.
The backend engine is RabbitMQ based and persists messages to CouchDB if necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>one system to rule them all</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2009/10/15/one-system-to-rule-them-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2009/10/15/one-system-to-rule-them-all/</guid>
      <description>One system to rule them all Here are the slides from my talk at erounge Wellington yesterday. It is about a workflow system I wrote in perl and erlang based on RabbitMQ and CouchDB. It is language independent and communicates with JSON messages.
RabbitMQ + CouchDB = AwesomeView more documents from Lenz Gschwendtner. And a direct link to the PDF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RabbitMQ for perl mongers</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2009/09/09/rabbitmq-talk-at-perlmongers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2009/09/09/rabbitmq-talk-at-perlmongers/</guid>
      <description>RabbitMQ for perl mongers
This is a short summary of the talk I gave yesterday at perl mongers Wellington about RabbitMQ and messaging in general and how to use it from perl.
The slides are on slideshare
RabbitMQ for Perl mongersView more documents from Lenz Gschwendtner. The git repositories are on github: http://github.com/norbu09 relevant repositories are: - net-amqp - Net_RabbitMQ_HTTP - RabbitIntro
There was a fair amount of interest in the topic so if some one wants to know more feel free to contact me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django like URL mapping in Catalyst - kind of</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2009/08/26/django-like-url-mapping-in-catalyst---kind-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2009/08/26/django-like-url-mapping-in-catalyst---kind-of/</guid>
      <description>Django like URL mapping in Catalyst - kind of
The problem I tried to solve is trivial, at least that was what I thought. I tried to remap URLs in one of our platforms to make it easy for others to adapt the way we call things. I18N related mostly. I have most of the things that might change in central config file already but figuring out how I actually get the URL map in there took a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>simple ssh tunnel script</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2009/08/04/simple-ssh-tunnel-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2009/08/04/simple-ssh-tunnel-script/</guid>
      <description>Simple ssh tunnel script When replicating CouchDB you need either VPN oder authentication or simply a SSH tunnel. No big deal normally a simple ssh -L... does the trick but I ended up with those SSH sessions that blocked ports and hung around and it was not the way to go in terms of automating rollouts where you need that port once and then never again.
A bit of googling brought up a script of the bacula guys that had the same problem and I adopted their script a bit to fit my needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git via HTTP (startup automation 3)</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2009/08/02/git-via-http-startup-automation-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2009/08/02/git-via-http-startup-automation-3/</guid>
      <description>Startup automation - Part 3 git via HTTP with nginx Just in case you don&amp;rsquo;t know (very unlikely) or never played with nginx before. This is the web server and frontend HTTP loadbalancer all your HTTP based setups should have anyway. There is documentation in English on the nginx wiki (http://wiki.nginx.org) and if you get stuck there is a lot of stuff just on google. The rails community love nginx and they tend to document well - a thanks at this point to those guys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RabbitMQ talk at erlounge</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2009/07/17/rabbitmq-talk-at-erlounge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2009/07/17/rabbitmq-talk-at-erlounge/</guid>
      <description>RabbitMQ talk at erlounge
This is a short summary of the talk I gave yesterday at erlounge Wellington about RabbitMQ and messaging in general.
The slides are now on slideshare
RabbitMQView more documents from norbu09. The git repositories are on github: http://github.com/norbu09 relevant repositories are: - RabbitIntro - Net_RabbitMQ_HTTP - net-amqp
The question about a frontend to RabbitMQ was answered today with this project that looks really promising: http://willcodeforfoo.com/2009/07/13/announcing-alice/
I hope you all enjoyed the talk and hope I could spark a bit of interest in the topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>puppet basics (startup automation 2)</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2009/06/14/puppet-basics-startautomation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2009/06/14/puppet-basics-startautomation/</guid>
      <description>Startup automation - Part 2 puppet basics In the last part of startup automation I talked you through the basics of configuring gitosis and the puppet config directory to make deployment of the config files really easy. Obviously we need some test clients and a working server now to play. I use parallels for local development and normally fire up one VM per project. I created an empty debian VM and just did a apt-get install puppet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>puppet and gitosis (startup automation 1)</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2009/06/10/gitosis-and-puppet-setup-startupautomation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2009/06/10/gitosis-and-puppet-setup-startupautomation/</guid>
      <description>Startup automation - Part 1 Startup automation became a big buzz currently but I think it has always been key to those who were successful. The speed to market is important and this is not only true for small companies.
Enough marketing blurb. Truth is we tech guys are lazy and that is a good habit. Laziness keeps us creative in terms of minimising tasks we have to do and that means in automating stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>many of us know it ...</title>
      <link>http://lnz.me/2009/02/09/many-of-us-know-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lnz.me/2009/02/09/many-of-us-know-it/</guid>
      <description>i guess many of us geeks went through the one or other phase in their life when they felt themselves trapped in the system with no way out. &amp;ldquo;the system&amp;rdquo; meaning any kind of mental state that prevented a clear view on the situation.
brenda just posted this URL and i can only encourage all to read it. keep it in mind and have a look at it when feeling unsure if that all out there that seems to lock you in is &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; or just you looking the wrong way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>